Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. World Advertising Forum (EPCOT) records, 1964-1984 and undated RL.11403
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. World Advertising Forum (EPCOT) records
1964-1984 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11403
3.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The World Advertising Forum was a meeting, held in 1984 at the EPCOT Center in Florida, of representatives from JWT worldwide offices to share creative ideas and solidify a global creative strategy. Collection includes correspondence, speeches, pamphlets and other printed materials, policy manuals and advertising case histories. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. World Advertising Forum (EPCOT) records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Artifacts and Memorabilia; J. Walter Thompson Company Corporate Documentation; J. Walter Thompson Company Iconographic Collection
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, speeches, pamphlets and other printed materials, policy manuals and advertising case histories. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- World Advertising Forum, 1964-1984 and undated; 1
  - 15-Second Commercials: How Will the Consumer React?, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Brief Review of Expenditures, Dimensions, Trends and Characteristics: JWT Media Department, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Cable Shop, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Changing Environment for Brand Marketing in the 1980s (Box 1)
  - Discussion of pretesting for Kodak, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Discussion on effective exposure, 1975 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT employee training/motivation Board away day, London, 1983 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT employee training/motivation, European Coordination, 1983 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT employee training/motivation, JWT Tokyo, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT German Swap Shop catalog, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT materials, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT presentation: Where Should We Be?, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT program agenda, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT speech, Don Johnston, 1984 (Box 1)
  - EPCOT transcripts from interviews and speeches, 1984; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - EPCOT transcripts from interviews and speeches, 1984; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - EPCOT welcoming packets, 1984 (Box 2)
  - EPCOT World Advertising Forum speeches, 1984; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - EPCOT Worldwide Managers Meeting, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Expanding Applications of SMRB Database, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Frankfurt Office: Deutschen Bank, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Frankfurt Office: R.J. Reynolds, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Guidelines for the Use and Selection of Celebrities in Advertising, 1978 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson Graduate Recruitment Seminar, 1984 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson USA Media Department, 1983 (Box 2)
  - JWT Media, 1984 (Box 3)
  - JWT Secretarial Handbook, undated (Box 3)
  - JWT Toronto brochure, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media contact procedures, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media evaluation systems available to JWT, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--ACTV or what's behind the smart black box, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--Family Weekly/Parade Blockbuster coupon, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--February Network Sweeps, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--Maxa Media Clock Media Analysis, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--Network television sports report, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media report--Prime Time Network Television, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Media reports--Cable and Advertising in the Eighties (London), 1983 (Box 3)
  - Media reports--Consumer Interest in Cable Television (London), 1983 (Box 3)
  - Media reports--General interest media projects, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Network television program schedule, 1983 (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--Australia Creative Annual, 1983 (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--Frankfurt: Dr. Koch's Trink, 1983 (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--Frankfurt: JWT Ein Portrait, 1980 (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--Frankfurt: JWT Plus, 1981 (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--Frankfurt: JWT Portrait 2, undated (Box 3)
  - New business brochures--JWT USA, 1983 (Box 4)
  - New business brochures--Manchester: JWT Manchester, 1984 (Box 4)
  - New business brochures--Manchester: The People of JWT Manchester, 1984 (Box 4)
  - New business brochures--Montreal: Day in the Life of a Creative Director, 1983 (Box 4)
  - New business brochures--New York: J. Walter Thompson New York, 1984 (Box 4)
  - New Ways of Seeing, 1984 (Box 4)
  - New York Office: Cartier "Signs of the Times". Undated (Box 4)
  - Plan for an Integrated Programme for Professional Development, European Region, undated (Box 4)
  - Product Naming Process, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Review of Advertising Copy Testing Techniques, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Review of cable television for Nestle, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Reports--Changing Role of the Consumer in the 1980s, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Reports--European sponsorship, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Reports--JWT USA Searching for Answers, Digital Solutions, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Reports--London sponsorhip, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Reports--New York Television Report, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Research, Reason and Risk, 1984 (Box 5)
  - San Francisco: Chevron "Creativity the Human Resource Project", 1983 (Box 5)
  - Scott Paper Company media review, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Secretarial training, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Seminar--Key Trends and Needs in Network Television Planning, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Seminar--Market Research Techniques, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Seminar--Proceedings from European Media Directors' Conference, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Some Things We Believe About JWT People, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Swap Shop order books, 1984; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - T-Plan, JWT London, 1964-1974; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Technical report on brand identity, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Valedictum: A Final Shot, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Very Personal View, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Zen and the Value of an Idling Engine; How Do We Get There? Don Johnston EPCOT summation, 1984 (Box 6)
  - JWT song, lyric sheet and cassette, undated (Box 7)
  - JWT Paris presentation, undated (Box 7)
  - New Business brochures--Hong Kong/IBM, 1984 (Box 7)
  - New Business brochures--Melbourne, 1984 (Box 7)